Yurii Basarada

yuriibasarada@gmail.com / 318-319-7335 / https://yuriibasarada.com / Chicago, IL

Summary

Full stack developer with seven years of experience, specializing in PHP, JavaScript, and MySQL. Deep experience in SaaS, e-commerce, cryptocurrency, Web3, and AI integrations. Experienced in leading teams of junior and mid-level developers, reviewing code, and managing staffing for technical projects.

Skills

Languages, Frameworks, and Libraries: PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, TypeScript, VueJs, ReactJs, NextJs, NuxtJs

Databases: SQL, NoSQL, MySQL, MariaDB, MongoDB

UI/UX Tools: HTML, CSS, Tailwind

Other: GIT, ChatGPT APIs, SaaS, NGINX, AWS, WordPress

Experience

Full Stack Developer

Upwork Freelance • Chicago, IL 03/2022 - 03/2024

Project: Developing data scraper for Oddseeker, a website that aggregates online gambling opportunities

- Designed and implemented a multi module architecture for the entire project.
- Engineered and delivered app, which leverages **CRON**, queues, and caching mechanisms to check the largest gaming casino resources for the presence of new games or updates for existing ones.
- Scraped over 20,000 games using individual modules for each resource and the **GPT** chat API for content generation.
- Implemented an interface to showcase these games to the client, further facilitating their integration into the client's main web application as a separate page for each game using generated content and scraped data.

Project: Improving coding flow, lighthouse metrics, and caching for Oddseeker website

- Improved task efficiency, in a team of five individuals, by implementing cutting-edge **Laravel** technologies, resulting in a 40% reduction in allotted time for project tasks completion.
- Implemented dynamic page generation, boosting the site's search engine ranking and significantly improving **SEO**.
- Implemented advanced caching mechanisms, optimized query execution time, and conducted in-depth analysis of media data, resulting in a 20% improvement in Lighthouse metrics.

Full Stack Developer

CUDEV • Kharkiv, UA 12/2019 - 03/2022

Project: Developing e-commerce template for easy implementation by client to quickly improve multiple websites

- Collaborated with a team of six to develop a responsive **e-commerce** template from the ground up, including managing a substantial user flow, with usage spikes exceeding 10,000 users per day.
- Implemented features such as comments, Google Pay, Apple Pay, PWA offline mode, reviews, and more.
- Achieved a 250% increase in sales across multiple e-commerce stores following the initial implementation of the template and successfully implemented template on more than 10 online stores.
- Led team of four including developers and project manager, conducted interviews, mentored new hires, and conducted code reviews, resulting in significant productivity improvements.
- Reduced release time by configuring testing flow and implementing CI/CD.

Project: Creating and improving management of websites for e-commerce client using AWS

- Led AWS e-commerce project for 50+ sites, enhanced management utilizing Google Sheets and CLI, resulting in a doubling of task speed.
- Implemented over 30 new medium and small-sized websites and deployed them using AWS: EC2/WorkMail, and the LAMP stack.
- Implemented Certbot on the server side, achieving a cost-saving of over 35% for all current and future websites.

BackEnd Developer

Toucan Solutions • Kharkiv, UA 03/2019 - 12/2019

Project: Developing warehouse management SaaS applications

- Developed and implemented an MVC (Model-View-Controller) architecture-based framework following SOLID principles, which was shared as a Composer package and applied in various other projects.
- Wrote unit tests and automated tests, leading to a 25% reduction in bug-related delays, as measured by the increased speed in completing subsequent tasks.
- Led a three-person team to build and successfully sell a Warehouse Management SaaS Applications based on the created framework. The product was sold to four different clients and subsequently supported.

Full Stack Developer

freelancer.com • Kharkive, UA 03/2018 - 03/2019

Project: Developing company portfolio with flexible editor

- Constructed a theme and multiple plugins, which formed the foundation for developing a fully editable WordPress backend.
- Integrated a fast-responsive **React JS** frontend, establishing communication through **GraphQL** between the two.
- Reduced the application size by 4 times through modifications and webpack configurations. Fully configured
 two domains for production and pre-production, implementing full automatic and functional testing before
 deployment.

Education

Master of Science (MS), Computer Science, 2018

International Economics and Humanities University • Ukraine